ADAM WILLIAMS

williams_adam@icloud.com linkedin.com/in/williams-adam github.com/awilliams Denver, CO

Profile

Professional software engineer with 13+ years experience. Focused on Go, clean code, quality, simplicity, and mentoring. Experience leading project development and working collaboratively as part of a distributed team.

Technical

Go (golang), Ruby, Javascript

Kubernetes, Docker, Helm

Puppet, Ansible

Swift, Python, PHP, Java

Git, SVN

Openstack, AWS, Linux

February 2015 - Present

Experience

Comcast

Engineer Level 4 Comcast Cable

Effectively design and implement an MPEG-TS parsing library in Go. Build application to monitor hundreds of video streams in order to provide metrics using Go, Docker, and Kubernetes.

Design and build native Go client for Apache Pulsar, collaborating with core project developers. Project was released as open-source by Comcast (github.com/Comcast/pulsar-client-go). Build distributed system for object replication.

Lead projects as "tech lead". Mentored fellow engineers. Participated in Open Source Fellowship Program.

Develop core components used for TCP & UDP custom protocol communications using Go. Follow specification documents to implement protocols.

Use Kubernetes and Helm for national deployment across multiple data centers. Develop custom CNI plugin.

Implement video decoding software using Go by following specification, allowing reduction in bandwidth and monitoring of key video distribution component.

Create custom network monitoring application. Uncover, debug, and resolve obscure longstanding DNS issue causing problems in production environments.

Setup automated testing, run load tests, analyze and correct performance problems.

Technologies Used:

- Go, Bash, Concourse, Drone
- Kubernetes, Docker, Helm, CNI, Linux

Cabify

October 2013 — February 2015

Senior Developer

cabify.com

Implement new features and modify existing functionality using RoR, Node.js, Go. Introduced Go to the company, which led to replacement of most Node.js services.

Provision and maintain servers with Ansible, Bash scripts, and Go binaries deployed on Linode and AWS in multiple regions for service provided in 4 countries. Monitor systems with InfluxDB and manage CouchDB replication/backups. Build internal tools used for development: chat bot for automated tasks, Github to Trello service, ssh/config management tool, and a dashboard / weekly automated email.

Technologies Used:

- Ruby on Rails (4.x) with Ruby 2.x
- CouchDB, Elasticsearch, Redis, ZeroMQ, Go, Node.js
- · Ansible, Linode
- Android

Incuentra Technologies

July 2010 — October 2013

Lead Developer

www.incuentra.es

Led project creation from idea to production stage. Design site architecture and programmed front and backends. Integrate with third parties via REST interfaces. Leverage Amazon's EC2, S3, RDS, and IAM services. Maintain servers using Chef and Unix tools. Continuous deployment with Capistrano. Write unit and integration tests. Localized version for Mexico.

Technologies Used:

- Ruby on Rails (2.x and 4.x) with Ruby 1.8.7 and 2.0.0
- MySQL, Solr
- VirtualBox, Vagrant, VeeWee, Ubuntu, Amazon Web Services
- Chef, Capistrano

DixiMedia

December 2008 — July 2010

Developer

www.lainformacion.com

Developed the online newspaper frontend using PHP and the Zend framework. Developed the CMS used by journalists with PHP

Just Landed

June 2008 - December 2008

Developer

www.justlanded.com / community.justlanded.com

Developed the Ruby on Rails website using MySQL database.

Ministerio de Educación

October 2007 - May 2008

Language and Conversation Assistant

English teacher in Spanish primary school.

MoCo Inc

May 2007 — October 2007

Web Developer

Collaborated with clients to provide solutions with Symphony framework in PHP.

Univ. of Minnesota Intercollegiate Athletics

September 2004 - May 2007

Web Developer

Developed intranet using a LAMP stack. Provided helpdesk support and live statistics for sporting events.

Interesting

Presenter at various Go and Ruby user groups

Co-organizer of Madrid Go meetup. Founder of internal Comcast Go club

Human Languages

English (native)

Spanish (fluent)

Education

University of Minnesota

Dual Major, B.S. Mathematics and B.A Spanish Studies

Adam Williams
williams_adam@icloud.com
awilliams.github.io/cv
linkedin.com/in/williams-adam